## Naseer Ahmed

#### Frontend Engineer

I am a highly skilled front-end developer with 4 years of experience in the software industry. I specialize in developing responsive websites using React.js with TypeScript. I have extensive experience in UI implementation and integration, and am committed to delivering high-quality code that meets project requirements.



thenaseer.dev@gmail.com

+923245503557

Lahore, pakistan

naseerdev.netlify.app/

linkedin.com/in/naseer-dev

github.com/naseerdev

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Frontend Developer

Kwanso

03/2022 - Present

Tasks

- Develop responsive and performant front-end code using React.js, TypeScript, Material UI 5, and Styled Components, based on UI/UX designs, to ensure a high-quality user experience.
- Collaborate with back-end developers to integrate the front-end with API using Apollo GraphQL, ensuring seamless functionality and performance.
- Write clear, concise, and well-documented code, and participate in code reviews and testing to ensure the highest levels of quality and reliability.
- Optimize code and processes to improve performance, reduce page load times, and enhance user experience.

# **UI Engineer**Nextbridge Ltd

08/2021 - 03/2022

Achievements/Tasks

- Translate UI/UX designs into high-quality code using React.js and Tailwind CSS, ensuring that the code was responsive, efficient, and easy to maintain.
- Collaborate with designers, project managers, and backend developers to implement front-end solutions that met project requirements and user needs.
- Contribute to the development of reusable components and libraries, which reduced development time and improved code quality.

# Frontend Developer Codility Solutions

06/2019 - 08/2021

Achievements/Tasks

- Translated UI/UX designs into high-quality code using HTML, and CSS React and Rails projects.
- Contributed to the development of reusable components and libraries, which reduced development time.

## EDUCATION

**Bachelor Of Computer Science**University Of south Asia Lhr

#### **SKILLS**



### **PROJECTS**

Helmer (09/2022 - Present)

- https://helmer-portal-staging.herokuapp.com/
- Helmer legal is a law firm to protect the legal rights of clients throughout the State of New Jersey.

Imgry (03/2021 - 08/2022)

- https://app.imgry.com
- Imgry is a free-to-use online graphic design tool. Use it to create social media posts, presentations, posters, videos, logos, and more.

#### BoxCheck (09/2019 - 03/2022)

- https://dev.ship.boxcheck.com/
- BoxCheck manages the fastest, most accurate, and most costefficient delivery network in the US for wine, beer, and more.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Emerging Talent Award**

Received the Emerging Talent Award in Codility, an online platform for evaluating programming skills, for demonstrating exceptional problemsolving skills. The award recognized the ability to write efficient, reliable, and maintainable code

#### **LANGUAGES**

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency